A Guide to the Near East Foundation records Accessions 2009.104, 2010.002, 2010.020 FA406
Rockefeller Archive Center
- AC.2009.104: Near East Foundation records, 1915-2003; 1940-1980; AC 2009:104; 180 Cubic Feet 168 boxes, including 150 standard record storage boxes
  - Special Events
    - Jordan - Jash, 1966-1967 (Box 40)
    - Jordan - Boys' Clubs, 1959 (Box 40)
      - Photos, 2016:FA406:039 (Folder SF39)
    - Pictures 0f Boys' Club - Amman, Jordan, 1959 (Box 40)
    - Misc. Photos (loose material) (Box 40)
    - Amman, Jordan - Boy Scout Troup with Dr. Dooley (Box 40)
    - Boys Club in Jordan Youth Work - Scouting, 1973 (Box 40)
    - Occupied Jordan - Dr. Partridge's trip - NEF Plantings - also Nablus, 1971 April (Box 40)
    - Jordan - Pictorial reports, 1961 January (Box 40)
      - Photos, 2016:FA406:040 (Folder SF40)
    - Pictorial Reports - Jordan, 1959 September - December (Box 40)
      - Photos, 2016:FA406:041 (Folder SF41)
    - Photos - Jordan (loose material) (Box 40)
    - Jordan - Scouting & Group Pictures, 1973 (Box 40)
    - Cology College of Agriculture 1971 - Bunda College 1976, 1971-1976 (Box 40)
    - Ghana - Agricultural Administration, 1970 (Box 40A)
    - Dahomey - Grain Storage (Box 40A)
    - Togo - Agricultural Education (Box 40A)
    - Morocco - Improved Wheat Program (Box 40A)
    - Mali (Box 40A)
    - Malagasy Republic (Part 1 of 2), 1965 (Box 40A)
    - Malagasy Republic (Part 2 of 2), 1965 (Box 40A)
    - Malawi (Box 40A)
    - Libya - Higher Education (Box 40A)
    - Libya - Agriculture (Box 40A)
    - Lesotho - Liphiring Project, 1978 (Box 40A)
    - Annual Luncheon, 1977 (Box 40A)
    - Annual Luncheon, 1978 (Box 40A)
    - Annual Luncheon Ambassadors, 1978 (Box 40A)
    - Annual Luncheon Ambassador, 1978 (Box 40A)
    - Tickets for Luncheon & Letters Acknowledging, 1978 (Box 40A)
    - Annual Luncheon, 1978 (Box 41)
    - Annual Luncheon, 1978 (Box 41)
    - Annual Luncheon, 1978 (Box 41)
    - Lord Caradon - Luncheon, 1978 (Box 41)
    - Special Events - Washington Reception, 1974 (Box 41)
    - Washington DC Feb 26 - Iranian Embassy, 1967-1970 (Box 41)
    - F.R. Campaign (Special Events) - Dinner, 1963 (Box 41)
    - Annual Dinner, 1969 October 29 (Box 41)
    - Jordan - Minister of Agr. Luncheon, 1969 August 22 (Box 41)
    - Dinner in Honor of Cleveland E. Dodge, 1968 October 23 (Box 41)
    - Special Events: Shah's Dinner - Music, Flowers, Menu, 1962 (Box 41)
    - Luncheon in Honor of UN Ambassador Mehdi or Iran, 1966 Novmeber 30 (Box 41)
    - Coronation Dinner - Shah & Empress of Iran, 1967 (Box 41)
    - Coronation Dinner, 1967 October (Box 41)
    - Coronation Dinner, 1967 October (Box 41)
    - Lila Acheson Wallace - garden party, 1966 September 10 (Box 41)
    - Golden Anniversary Dinner (folder unlabeled), 1965 (Box 41)
    - Sponsors, Golden Anniversary, 1965-1966 (Box 41)
    - Golden Anniversary Dinner Committee - Correspon., 1966 (Box 41)
    - Letters of Acceptance - Dinner Committee, 1966 (Box 41)
    - Daily Sheet - Golden Anniversary Dinner, 1966 (Box 41)
    - Dinner Committee - Members, 1965-1966 (Box 41)
    - Golden Anniversary, 1965-1966 (Box 41)
    - Dr. E. Alton Partridge, 1966 (Box 41)
    - Society Prospects, 1965 (Box 41)
    - Dinner Committee List, 1966 (Box 41)
    - Golden Anniversary Dinner - Invitations to the Press, 1966 (Box 41)
    - Special Events - Cosmopolitan Club Tea, 1966 April (Box 41)
    - Regrets for Dinner, 1966 (Box 41)
    - Roosevelt Cocktail Party, 1965-1966 (Box 41)
    - Golden Anniversary Bulletin, 1965-1966 (Box 41)
    - Special Guests - List, etc., 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Golden Anniversary Dinner, 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence - Dinner Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 41A)
    - DAIS Guests - Correspondence, etc., 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Golden Anniversary Dinner, 1966 April 25 (Box 41A)
    - Golden Anniversary Record & Leadership Statement, 1967 (Box 41A)
    - Golden Anniversary Sponsors List/Golden Anniv. Dinner Committee Contribution List, 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Golden Anniversary Dinner - Addresses by Badeau & Allen, 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Mrs. Dodge Personal Friends, 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Mr. Perkins' Luncheon - March 14 - University Club - 12:30 p.m., 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Richard Perkins (Company) - Letters to Dinner Committee, 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Cleveland Dodge - Letters to Dinner Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 41A)
    - Richard S. Perkins' Letters RE Hon. Comm., 1966 February 10 (Box 41A)
    - Richard S. Perkins - Letters to Dinner Committee, 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Letters of Regret - Honorary Committee - Richard S. Perkins Letter, 1966 February 10 (Box 41A)
    - Diplomatic Corps - List, etc., 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Perkins' Letters to Board Members, 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Letters of Regret - Dinner Committee, 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Publicity Release - Sponosrs for Golden Anniversary, 1965 April (Box 41A)
    - Golden Anniversary - Sponsors List, 1965-196 (Box 41A)
    - Golden Anniversary Dinner - Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Golden Anniversary Dinner - News Releases, 1966 (Box 41A)
    - Richard S. Perkins Luncheon - University Club, 1966 March 29 (Box 41A)
    - Kermit Roosevelt Cocktail Party - Knickerbocker Club, 1966 February 15 (Box 41A)
    - YWCA Luncheon, 1965 October 20 (Box 41A)
    - Halazoun Luncheon, 1965 September 28 (Box 42)
    - Cleveland E. Dodge - Luncheon Unviersity Club, 1965 April 27 (Box 42)
    - Dinner G.A., 1962-1966 (Box 42)
    - Special Events - Golden Ann. Dinner-Hotel Corres. (Box 42)
    - Dinner in Honor of King Hussein of Jordan, 1964 April 16 (Box 42)
    - (loose material), 1959-1960 (Box 42)
    - Business Men's Luncheon, 1959 October 20 (Box 42)
    - Tribute Letters to Herbert Hoover, 1963 (Box 42)
    - King Hussein Dinner, 1959 April 14 (Box 42)
    - Near East Dinner Dance - General File No. 1, 1961 January 26 (Box 42)
    - Invitations, Letters of Check Return, List of Honorary Committee (Box 42)
    - Hoover Dinner Preliminaries, 1963 (Box 42)
    - Cleveland E. Dodge - Tribute Dinner to Hoover, 1963 December 12 (Box 42)
    - Frank H. Berend - Tribute Dinner to Hoover, 1963 December 12 (Box 42)
    - List & Acceptance Sheets from Berend (Mr. Cline's Copy) (Box 42)
    - Mrs. Robert Howe Baldwin - Tribute Dinner to Herbert Hoover, 1963 December 12 (Box 42)
    - Board Members (NEF) - Tribute Dinner, 1963 December 12 (Box 42)
    - Embassies - Tribute Dinner to Hoover, 1963 December 12 (Box 42)
    - Herbert Hoover - Tribute Dinner, 1963 December 12 (Box 42)
    - Herbert Hoover, Jr. - Tribute Dinner - Allen Hoover, 1963 December 12 (Box 42)
    - Honorary Chairman - Tribute Dinner to Herbert Hoover, 1963 December 12 (Box 42)
    - Mr. Howard Page - Tribute Dinner to Hoover, 1963 December 12 (Box 42)
    - Waldorf Astoria - Tribute Dinner, 1963 December 12 (Box 42)
    - Dr. Allen, Retirement Dinner, 1957 (Box 42)
    - A, 1963 (Box 42)
    - B, 1963 (Box 42)
    - C, 1963-1964 (Box 42)
    - D, 1963 (Box 42)
    - E, 1963 (Box 42)
    - F, 1963 (Box 42)
    - G, 1963 (Box 42)
    - H, 1963 (Box 42)
    - I, 1963 (Box 42)
    - J, 1963 (Box 42)
    - K, 1963 (Box 42)
    - L, 1963 (Box 42)
    - M, 1963 (Box 42)
    - N, 1963 (Box 42)
    - O, 1963 (Box 42)
    - P, 1963 (Box 42)
    - Q, 1963 (Box 42)
    - R, 1963 (Box 42)
    - S, 1963 (Box 43)
    - T, 1963 (Box 43)
    - U, 1963 (Box 43)
    - V, 1963 (Box 43)
    - W, 1953 (Box 43)
    - X, 1963 (Box 43)
    - Y, 1963 (Box 43)
    - Z, 1963 (Box 43)
    - Special Events - Aram Luncheon - Text of Address, 1963-1964 (Box 43)
    - Special Events - Aram Luncheon - Regrets & Accpt, 1963-1964 (Box 43)
    - Diner in Honor of Shah & Empress of Iran, 1962 (Box 43)
    - Special Events - Near East Dinner Dance for Benefit of Ghaleh Nou, 1961 (Box 43)
    - Special Events - Aram Luncheon - Department of State Info, 1962 (Box 43)
    - 25th Anniversary - Dinner, 1955 February 7 (Box 43)
    - Special Events - Shah's Dinner - Speeches, Awards at Dinner, 1962 (Box 43)
    - Special Events - Shah's Dinner - News Coverage, 1962 (Box 43)
    - NEF Acheson - New Approach to Old Problems (Box 43)
    - NEF - Allen, Archer - Reader's Digest Discussion "A Friend in Deed in Need", 1947 (Box 43)
    - NEF - H.B. Allen - Rural Education & Welfare in the Middle East, 1944 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Allen - Royal Central Asian Journal (Book Review), 1947 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Allen - Scientific Advisory Mission Report, 1944 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Archer - Reports of Foreign Director, 1934-1952 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Archer - Program for the Times Lifestock - Improvement "Food & Agriculture", 1950 January - March (Box 43)
    - NEF - Archer - "Don't Underestimate Modest Men" Your Life, 1946 December (Box 43)
    - NEF - Badeau - Around the World - American Town Meeting, 1949 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Survey Mid-monthly - Leadership with World Horizons - Allen T. Burns, 1947 April (Box 43)
    - NEF - CIER - Value of American Efforts for Reconstruction, 1947-1949 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Committee on Foreign Affairs "Voluntary Foreign Aid" A Study, 1948 (Box 43)
    - Property of Florence S. Duryea - Women's Club in Greece, 1911-1936 (Box 43)
    - Meals for Millions - NEF - Eyer pg. 49, 1951 (Box 43)
    - NEF - In The Minds of Men - Dorothea S. Frank - Dept. of State, 1946 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Dept. State Field Reporter - "Have We Inormation Know-How" Dyle Hayden, 1952 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Lyle Hayden - Christian Herald -"Lyle Hayden - Shirt Sleeve Ambassador", 1949 November (Box 43)
    - W. David Hooper - Development of Agriculture in Developing Countries, 1976 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Home Economics in the Near East, 1947 (Box 43)
    - NEF - p.70 - International Welfare Directory, 1952 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Building Roads to Peace - Inst. International Education, 1969 (Box 43)
    - NEF - News Bulletin - Institute of International Education p23-p50, 1948-1955 (Box 43)
    - Thomas Jesse Jones - "In Memoriam", 1930 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Miller - "Accounting for Charity's Millions" Harold R. Caffyn - Journal of Accountancy, 1928 August (Box 43)
    - NEF - Miller - Consultative Conference with Representatives of Foundations, 1951 April 18-19 (Box 43)
    - Evolution of Democracy - Francis M. Rust, 1923 (Box 43)
    - NEF - Readers Digest - A Way To Lessen World Hunger, 1950 (Box 43)
    - Sage Foundation - Adm. of Relief Abroad - Near East Relief, 1915-1930 (Box 43)
    - Sage Foundation - Adm. of Relief Abroad - Germany, Spain, France & Russia, 1918-1925 (Box 43)
    - Sage Foundation - Adm. Of Relief Abroad - American Red Cross, 1917-1919 (Box 43)
    - President Truman - Point Four, 1949-1953 (Box 43)
    - NEF - "Education of the Handicapped" UNESCO, 1949 (Box 43)
    - Dept. State Bulletin - NEF Personnel References, 1943 May 15 (Box 44)
    - NEF - Organizations Working in Field Post - War Reconstruction, 1942 (Box 44)
    - NEF - U.S. Bilateral Technical Assistance U.S. Voluntary Agencies, 1949 (Box 44)
    - American Committee for Relief in Near East - John Kingsbury - Pictures - Near East Relief News, 1919-1963 (Box 44)
    - Near East Foundation Newsletters - Yule Tidings, Overseas Bulletin, 1933, 1935 (Box 44)
    - Correspondence - King Hussein (loose material), 1959 (Box 44)
  - Special Formats
    - Liberia (Box 41)
    - Middle East, 1982-1985 (Box 41)
    - Sudan, 1982-1985 (Box 41)
    - Uganda - B. Thompson, Mr. Wood (Box 41)
    - Egypt, 1987-1988 (Box 41)
    - Gambia (Box 41)
    - Lebanon, 1990 (Box 41)
    - Lebanon, 1989 (Box 41)
    - Jordan, 1967-1969 (Box 41)
    - Sudan (Box 41)
    - 1980-1990 (Box 41)
    - 1965-1980 (Box 41)
    - Iran & Jordan, 1945-1965 (Box 41)
    - Lesotho, 1989 (Box 41)
    - Photos (Box 41)
    - Central African Republic, 1956-1966 (Box 41)
    - Jordan, 1979 (Box 41)
    - Misc. & Unidentified Pictures, 1978 (Box 41)
    - Negatives RRDP Report, 1964 (Box 41)
    - Women's Committee Dinner Dance, 1961 (Box 41)
    - Afghanistan, 1965 (Box 41)
    - Bhutan, 1983 (Box 41)
    - Botswana (Box 41)
    - Technicians - Fall/Winter, also Dr. Loeweinstein pix of Togo, Ghana, 1974-1975 (Box 41)
    - Greece (Box 41)
    - 1988 Annual Report - Photos, Text, etc., 1988-1989 (Box 41)
    - Near East Foundation Staff & Building Photographs, 1947-1978 (Box 41)
    - Africa (Box 41)
    - Iran, 1975-1976 (Box 41)
    - Jordan: Jash Report, 1970 (Box 42)
    - 70th Anniversary Reception Photos, 1985 (Box 42)
    - Oversized Photos Mounted - Jordan, Greece, Liberia, 1984 (Box 42)
    - Annual Luncheon, 1976-1977 (Box 42)
    - NEF Staff Negatives (Box 42)
    - Photos & Negatives Annual Report, 1984 (Box 42)
    - Annual Report, 1977 (Box 42)
    - Annual Report - Photos, Text, etc., 1986 (Box 42)
    - Annual Report - Photos, Text, etc., 1987 (Box 42)
    - Swaziland, 1980 (Box 42)
    - NEF Building, Tanzania (Box 42)
    - UNRWA (United Nations Relief & Works Agency) (Box 42)
    - Upper Volta, 1967-1974 (Box 42)
    - Kenya, 1977 (Box 42)
    - Lebanon, 1984-1985 (Box 42)
    - Lesotho, 1984-1986 (Box 42)
    - Morocco, 1970 (Box 42)
    - Niger, 1966-1971 (Box 42)
    - Iran, 1971 (Box 44)
    - Africa - Several countries (Box 44)
    - Colby College - Malawi, 1969-1971 (Box 44)
    - Operation Insight, 1960 (Box 44)
    - Jordan - Amman (Box 44)
    - Jiro - Development, 1976 (Box 44)
    - Moghan Argo - Industry, 1977 (Box 44)
    - Jiroft Development Organization, 1977 (Box 44)
    - Caspian Sea, 1976 (Box 44)
    - Ahwaz, 1977 (Box 44)
    - Community Development Album - Chejudo - James E. Johnson - C.D. Adviser, 1960-1961 (Box 80)
    - Unlabeled Photo Album showing various locations (Box 80)
    - NEF Project Photo Album, 1986-4987 (Box 80)
    - Egypt/Sudan ex: Roger Hardister, 1987 (Box 80)
    - NEF Project Scrapbook, 1954 - 1965 May; 2016:FA406:031 (Box 85)
    - NEF Project Scrapbook, 1954 - 1965 May; 2016:FA406:031 (Box 85)
    - NEF Project Scrapbook, 1965 May - 1967; 2016:FA406:031 (Box 85)
    - Box of Negatives - Africa (Box 86)
    - Box of negatives - I. House (Box 86)
    - Box of Negatives - AFME Box 1, 1956-1960 (Box 12)
      Separated Materials
      These photographic materials have been separated from the paper records for special handling and rehousing.
    - Box of Negatives - AFME (box 3), 1955 November 28 - 1958 June (Box 87)
    - Box of Negatives - AFME (box 2), 1958 July 8 - 1967 May 17 (Box 87)
    - 4 Boxes of Negatives - B/NEF Archives Negatives 1-54/55-109-177/178-228, 2009:104:127 (Box 87)
    - 17 Audio Cassettes with Various Titles, 2009:104:118 (Box 87)
    - Box of Negatives "Africa", 2009:104:115 (Box 87)
    - Box of Negatives "Africa", 2009:104:116 (Box 87)
    - Iran, 2009:104:113 (Box 87)
    - Jordan, 2009:104:112 (Box 87)
    - Greece, 2009:104:114 (Box 87)
    - History of Tomorrow, 2009:104:117 (Box 87)
    - History of Tomorrow (Box 87)
    - History of Tomorrow (Box 87)
    - Cassette Tapes (12) (Box 87)
    - Cassette Tapes (Box 87)
    - Miscellaneous: photo negatives, slide negatives, glass plates, film neg. albums (Box 127)
    - Miscellaneous: NEF Archive negatives, History of Tomorrow slide presentation, negatives, awards, articles & NEF memorabilia, etc (Box 128)
    - Oversize - Poster - Near East Relief, 2009:104:190 (Box 131)
    - Oversize - Poster - What Others Say About the NER, 2009:104:191 (Box 131)
    - Oversize - Poster - I am Tired, 2009:104:195 (Box 131)
    - Oversize - Poster - I am Tired, 2009:104:196 (Box 131)
    - Oversize - Poster - Through a Near East, 2009:104:197 (Box 131)
    - Making Room and His Star of Hope (Posters back to back - 2 copies of each), 2009:104:198 (a) (Box 131)
    - Waiting to Get In, 2009:104:198(b) (Box 131)
    - Armenia, Land of the Living - Photos of Transcaucasian Russia, 2009:104:192 (Box 131)
    - Inside the Gates, 2009:104:199 (Box 131)
    - Their Life Lines (2 copies), 2009:104:200 (Box 131)
    - The Empty Bowl - 2 posters, 2009:104:201 (Box 131)
    - In the Hollow of Your Hand, 2009:104:202 (Box 131)
    - Work Chart, 2009:104:203 (Box 131)
    - Near East Relief, 2009:104:204 (Box 131)
    - Redeem the Children Appointed Unto Death, 2009:104:205 (Box 131)
    - Why Near East Relief, 2009:104:206 (Box 131)
    - Bundle Station, 2009:104:207 (Box 131)
    - Temporary Passport, Egyptian Expeditionary Force (Box 131)
    - NER Service Medal Certificate, 2009:104:193 (Box 131)
    - Sentenced to Die, 2009:104:194 (Box 131)
    - This Elevator Receives of Corn and Wheat for...NEF, 2009:104:188 (Box 131)
    - 1st American Hanovskaya Gratuitous Dining Room for Poor Child, 1919 June 29 - 1922 (Box 133)
    - NEF Memorabilia (Box 133)
    - Near East Industries (Box 133)
    - Displacement - Armenian Refugees (Box 133)
    - Personnel - Photos & articles about past employees (Box 133)
    - Caucasus: Alexandropol orphanage (Box 133)
    - NER Memorabilia on Armenia and the American Committee for Armenian & Syrian Relief (Box 133)
    - NER - Vocational training and work (Box 133)
    - NEF Appeals (Box 133)
    - NEF - Caucasus: Baptism Ritual (Box 133)
    - NEF - Caucasus: Bolshevism (Box 133)
    - E.M. Bulkley (Box 133)
    - Antilyas Playground, 2016:FA406:042 (Folder SF42)
    - Portrait - Barclay Acheson (Box 133)
    - Portrait - Cleveland Dodge (Box 133)
    - Portrait - unnamed (Box 133)
    - Photographs - Old Overseas Staff (Box 133)
    - Iran General (Box 133)
    - Near East/New York - NEF & American Philanthropy Exhibition (Box 134)
    - Neery Melkonian File - Concerning Exhibition (Box 134)
    - Exhibition material (Box 134)
    - Material for exhibition includes CD (Box 134)
    - Delmar J. Dooley - Employment positions (Box 134)
    - Appeal Literature & Publications - NER Vol. I Historical, 1924-1925 (Box 134)
    - Some of the Appeal Literature & Publications NEF Vol. II (in process), 1949 (Box 134)
    - Appeal Literature & Publications - NER Vol. II Historical, 1924-1925 (Box 134)
    - Appeal Literature & Publications - NEF Vol. I, 1930-1948 (Box 134)
    - The 1931 Thesaurus (Box 134)
    - Nurses Training & Caucauses (daily life, orphanages & refugees) - photo box (Box 140)
    - Album #6 Acheson Collection 369-819 (Box 141)
    - Album #3: Personnel; New York; Caucasus Personnel; NE Pictures mostly 1922; Apartment in Constantinople; Pat's views of Kamakura (Box 142)
    - C - Small Photographs - Gift from the Estate of H.C. Jaquith (Box 143)
    - Archival Staff Photographs: Dodd - Mayston (Box 144)
    - Archival Staff Photographs: Miller - Zog (Box 145)
    - NER Material from the 1920s (Box 146)
    - Album #2 Orphanages: Orphanages: Caucasus; Mostly Russian taken by Jackson; Rufugee and children feeding; 1922 NE Orphans - French Exposition; Alexandropoulos; Polygon Parades (Box 147)
    - Album #1: Volga Trips: Pictures by Maynard Owen Williams (Volga); other pictures by M.O. Williams (not Volga); General NE Pictures & Doc. Pics. (Box 148)
    - Album #5 - Miscellaneous (Box 149)
    - album #6 Acheson Collection 1 - 366 (Box 150)
    - A - Letters/Correspondence - Gift from the Estate of H.C. Jaquith (Box 151)
    - Album #4 Travels: Iraq - trip to Baghdad & Persia with Monroe; Syria/Lebanon/Petra; Greece; Misc. mostly Europe; Constantinople scenes - Persia; Cairo; Pacific Coast & other US shots (Box 152)
    - Project Photos - Archival (Box 153)
    - Archival Staff photographs: Acheson - Dietrick (Box 154)
    - Album with photos of Alexandrople: Caucauses; Constantinople (Box 155)
    - C- NEF Archives - Large Photographs; Restored Photographs. G- Maps & Atlas (Box 156)
    - MCNY Exhibition - Original objects on paper-framed (Box 157)
    - MCNY Exhibition - Original Objects on paper-framed (Box 158)
    - Acheson Photo Negatives 1 - 821 (incl. glass plates) (Box 159)
    - Acheson Misc. Prints and Postcards (Box 159)
    - Acheson - Negative Albums (6) (Box 159)
    - NEF Ancient/ Modern Iran / lebanon, Jordan - 3 Slide Carousels plus Stand Loupe, 2009:104:181-183 (Box 134)
    - 55 sheets of colored slides from various NEF countries (mostly the Middle East); plus 4 Carousel Slide Trays, 2009:104:188-2009:104:242 (Box 134)
    - 4 Slide Carousels, 2009:104:184 - 2009:104:187 (Box 134)
    - Album containing sketches as children. Inscribed: "Deepest thanks from Children of Suffering Georgia to Freethinking Generous America from the American Georgievskaja dining room. Prince S.V. Tseretelly" (Box 162)
    - Greek Occupation Posters (Folder 1)
    - Oversize Photographs, NEF Archives (Folder 2)
    - Honors/Awards; Near East Relief Service Medal (2) In Appreciation - Honor Roll of Benefactors (1) (Box 163)
    - Large collection of checks from NEF made out to Amman, Jordan from 1978 to 1980 (Box 163)
    - Audio Cassettes
      Special formats such as photographs, moving image, and oversized paper items have been separated for specialized handling and storage.
  - Committees
    - Investment Committee (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Executive Committee Notice of Meetings, 1964 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Finance Committee Action on Investment, 1960 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Planning & Policy Committee, 1959 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Executive Committee Dockets, 1959-1960 (Box 89)
    - Board of Directors - Development Program Luncheon at the Down Town Assocn., 2/5/59 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Finance Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Director - Executive Committee Notice of Meetings, 1959-1960 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Minutes of Meetings, 1959 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Dockets (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Finance Committee, 1958 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - List of Members, 1958 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Minutes, 1958 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Notice of Meetings, 1958 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Dockets, 1957 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Finance Committee, 1957 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Board of Directors - Minutes, 1957 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Program Committee, 1957 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Finance Committee, 1956 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Program Committee, 1956 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Program Committee, 1955 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Program Committee, 1954 (Box 89)
    - Program Committee Minutes, 1955 (Box 89)
    - Subject - Finance Committee, 1954 (Box 89)
    - Program Committee Minutes, 1954 (Box 89)
    - Board of Directors' Correspondence, 1984 (Box 89)
    - Board of Directors Correspondence, 1983 (Box 89)
    - Board of Directors Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 89)
    - Board of Directors Correspondence, Prior 1981 (Box 89)
    - Board of Directors - Attendance Record (Box 89)
    - Book Distribution to Board Members Randal's "Going All The Way", 12/83 (Box 89)
    - Board of Directors' Votes on Aid to Cambodia (Through Oxfam) (Box 89)
    - Material on BLDG. Distributed To Board Members (Box 89)
    - Prospective Board Members (Box 89)
    - Audit Committee (Box 89)
    - Development Committee (Box 89)
    - Subject - Program Committee, 1954 (Box 84)
    - Subject - Finance Committee, 1954 (Box 84)
    - Program Committee Minutes, 1954 (Box 84)
    - Employees Admin. Commtitee & Employees Benefit Fund Admin. Committee (Box 89)
    - Investment/Finance Committee, 1983 (Box 90)
    - Investment/Finance Committee, 1982 (Box 90)
    - Investment/Finance Committee, 1981 (Box 90)
    - Nominating Committee, 1983-1984 (Box 90)
    - Nominating Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 90)
    - Nominating Committee, 1978-1981 (Box 90)
    - Nominating Committee, 1965-1976 (Box 90)
    - NEF Program Committee (Box 90)
    - Special Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 90)
    - Special Committee - Cleveland E. Dodge Memorial, 1983 (Box 90)
    - Steering Committee (Box 90)